Robert J. Nixon

21 Grebe Road, Bicester | 07557023792 | robert@robertnixon.net

Experience

Bicester Town Council

Councillor • May 2019 - Present

Green Party councillor representing Bicester East

Sophos

Software Engineer • July 2019 - September 2019

Global Academy Jobs

Junior Web Developer • April 2018 - June 2019

Key Responsibilities

 Applying technical knowledge to a social enterprise project called The Global Academy. Providing technical knowledge to the decision making process and developing features required for the project website

theglobalacademy.ac

- Writing and maintaining Python scripts used to retrieve job advertisements from client's jobs boards and import them into the GAJobs website ready for moderation.
- Deploying these Python scripts onto a virtual machine running on MS Azure.
- Editing and uploading job advertisements to Global Academy Jobs' academic jobs board.

Technologies Used

Python, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Git Version Control, Drupal, MS Azure

Summary

I joined Global Academy Jobs at the end of my first year of university. After 1 month I was offered a 10 week full time internship part funded by Santander's Universities SME internship scheme. After this I've continued completing various technical tasks whilst progressing with my university studies.

Develop 1 Ltd

Work Experience Student • July 2016

I joined Develop 1 for a week of work experience after finishing my AS Levels. Whilst there I worked on managing and maintaining SQL databases with MS server management studio. I also learned about the admin side of running a small business, for example I was put in change of calculating the expenses for the company for the past year.

Education

Oxford Brookes University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science • 2017 — 2020

Current GPA = 4.0

Wheatley Park School

A-Levels • 2015 — 2017

Achieved Grade A Mathematics, Grade B Computer Science and Grade C Physics. In addition Grade C AS Further Mathematics and Grade A Level 3 Extended Project Qualification.

The Cooper School

GCSEs • 2010 - 2015

11 GCSEs grades A* - B including A grades in Mathematics and B grades in English

Volunteer Experience

North Oxfordshire Green Party

Various Roles • 2015 — Present

Chair (2018 - Present): - I'm responsible for the overall running of the branch. This includes organizing and chairing meetings, helping to oversee the direction of the party locally and running events.

Web Developer (2015 - Present):- Before I joined the Green Party my local branch had no website and were reliant of Facebook and Twitter for their online presence. I created a website for them and have continued the update and adapt it as requirements change. You can find the website at

nogp.org.uk

Co-chair (2017-2018)

Membership Secretary (2017 - Present): - I manage the branch membership records. This includes using CiviCRM and making sure that members are informed about news and upcoming events.

Vice Chair (2015 - 2017): - I assisted the Chair with the overall running of the branch including the organization and chairing of meetings and the organization of events.

South East Young Greens

Elections officer • 2019 — Present

The Green Party of England and Wales

Party Member • 2015 — Present

Skills

Political campaigning

Local election campaign management, volunteers coordination, fundraising, public speaking.

Languages and Software Development Tools

Python, Java, C, C++, HTML, Markdown, LaTeX, CSS, JavaScript, Git Version Control, NetBeans, PyCharm, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code

Operating Systems

Linux/Unix, Windows

Other Software Tools

GIMP, Kdenlive, LibreOffice, MS Office, Google Drive

Outside Interests

- Computers and Computer Science
- · Green Politics
- · Gaming on Linux
- Linux and FOSS in general
- Electric vehicles and other low/zero emission transport

Social Links

- Github: https://github.com/robnixon
- Twitter: http://twitter.com/_robertjnixon
- Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/the.robert.j.nixon
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertjosephnixon/
- Website: https://robertnixon.net